JEN MCPHAIL

website: jenmcphail.com email: mcphail.jen@gmail.com github: github.com/jenmcphail

about me

I'm a full-stack web developer specializing in JavaScript and Ruby. In a previous life, I managed creative teams and clients in digital marketing. I enjoy minimalist design, silent films, bagels, and fluffy dogs.

projects

- Diversi-speak: Current work in progress. Inspired by Iheanyi Ekechukwu's list of diverse people in tech who want a platform on which to speak, I am building an app using Angular and Firebase that allows event organizers to browse each speaker's bio and background.
 Foodly: Developed a Ruby on Rails app in a team of 4 that matches users with local restaurants. I built the database structure in postgreSQL and implemented the Stripe API to handle monthly subscription payments.
- **BuffyWiki:** Created a *Buffy The Vampire Slayer* themed app during a one-week sprint using Ruby, Sinatra, postgreSQL, and Bootstrap.
- Hangman Browser Game: Built using frontend JS, JQuery, and DOM manipulation.

skills

Front End Dev: HTML5 • CSS3 • SASS • JavaScript • JQuery • Angular • React • Redux

Back End Dev: Ruby • Rails • Sinatra • SQL
postgreSQL • Node • Express • MongoDB
Webpack • Grunt • Unit Testing / TDD

Design: Adobe Creative Suite: InDesign,

Photoshop, Illustrator • Wireframing • Sketch

Other: Agile team and project management • Client Maintenance • Digital Marketing • CMS

experience

Sept 2016 to Current

May 2016 to Aug 2016

Feb 2015 to April 2016

Aug 2013 to Aug 2014

• Freelance Web Developer - San Francisco,

CA: Currently working on a number of front -end web development projects. My process includes ideation, wireframing, coding fully-responsive websites in HTML, CSS, and JS, optionally implementing CMS, and providing guidance on digital marketing best-practices.

• Web Development Immersive - General Assembly, San Francisco, CA: Completed a 12-week intensive program to move from a coding hobbyist to a full-stack web developer. Built fully responsive apps in solo and agile group settings using modern languages and frameworks and industry best-practices like object-oriented programming, version control through git, and test-driven development.

• Account Manager - Codeword Agency, New York, NY: Drove content program activities, including content creation, activations, strategic initiatives, and measurement. Communicated between clients and internal teams to own process steps, budget and scope requirements, client reviews, feedback, and final delivery.

• Tech Specialist - Hofstra University: Assisted Hofstra University students, alumni, and faculty in navigating the university's IT system and campus network. Troubleshooted and repaired connectivity and software issues.

education

Aug 2011 to Aug 2014 **Hofstra University:** BA Public Relations • Cum Laude • 4.0 Major GPA • Business Minor

- Sigma Delta Alph Advertising Honors Society
- Public Relations Student Society of America